- HI-YAH!
- 嗨呀！
SQUIDWARD!
章鱼哥！
SORRY, BUDDY.
DIDN'T SEE YOU.
对不起，伙计。
没看到你。
ARE YOU OKAY?
你还好吗？
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
WHAT KIND OF UNFORESEEN
YET COMPLETELY PREDICTABLE
什么样的不可预见的情况
但完全可预测
STUPIDITY HAVE YOU
RUINED MY DAY WITH THIS TIME?
你愚蠢吗
这次毁了我的一天？
- OH.
- 哦。
I'M JUST PRACTICING
MY KARATE CHOPS.
我只是在练习
我的空手道排骨。
I'M GOING TO HAVE
AN INTENSE KARATE SESSION
我将会有
激烈的空手道课程
WITH SANDY LATER.
稍后与桑迪一起。
SANDY SAYS, "YOU NEVER KNOW
WHAT KIND OF CREEPY CREEPER
桑迪说：“你永远不知道
什么样的令人毛骨悚然的爬行者
COULD BE CREEPING CREEPILY
AROUND ANY CREEPY CORNER."
可能会令人毛骨悚然
在任何令人毛骨悚然的角落。”
- PARANOID MUCH?
- 偏执多了？
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
SORRY, SQUIDWARD.
对不起，章鱼哥。
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
ONE OF THOSE CREEPY CREEPERS.
我以为你是
那些令人毛骨悚然的爬行者之一。
YOU KNOW, SQUIDWARD,
YOU REALLY SHOULD LEARN
你知道，章鱼哥，
你真的应该学习
HOW TO PROTECT YOURSELF.
如何保护自己。
MAYBE YOU'D LIKE TO JOIN US?
也许您想加入我们？
- WELL...
- 出色地...
NOPE.
没有。
I HAVE MORE
IMPORTANT THINGS TO DO.
我还有更多
重要的事情要做。
- OKEY-DOKEY, SQUIDWARD.
- 好啦，章鱼哥。
STOP ON BY LATER IF YOU CHANGE
YOUR MIND ABOUT THE KARATE.
如果您有改变，请稍后停止
您对空手道的看法。
- I WON'T.
- 我不会。
- [faint wheeze]
- [微弱的喘息声]
- H-HELLO?
- 你-你好？
IS SOMEBODY THERE?
有人在吗？
UM, HELLO?
嗯，你好？
IT'S CONSIDERED RUDE
NOT TO ANSWER.
这被认为是粗鲁的
不回答。
[nervous chuckle]
WHAT DO YOU GOT,
[紧张的笑声]
你有什么，
COTTON IN YOUR EARHOLES?
你的耳洞里有棉花吗？
[nervous laughter]
[紧张的笑声]
[gulps]
[吞咽]
I'VE GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE.
我必须离开这里。
[yelping]
[尖叫]
SPONGEBOB!
[knocking furiously]
海绵宝宝！
[猛烈地敲门]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- OH WAIT,
I-I DON'T GET IT.
- 哦等等，
我-我不明白。
- SPONGEBOB!
- 海绵宝宝！
SPONGEBOB!
OPEN UP!
海绵宝宝！
打开！
- SQUIDWARD?
- 章鱼哥？
- HURRY, SPONGEBOB.
- 快点，海绵宝宝。
- SQUIDWARD,
WHAT'S WRONG?
- 章鱼哥，
怎么了？
- YOU WERE...
RIGHT.
- 你是...
对。
- I WAS?
ABOUT WHAT?
- 我是？
关于什么？
- ABOUT HOW DANGER
LURKS AROUND EVERY CORNER.
- 关于有多危险
潜伏在每个角落。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- UM, SQUIDWARD?
- 嗯，章鱼哥？
IT'S JUST GARY.
这只是加里。
- [mewing]
- [喵喵叫]
- HEY, I SHOULD HAVE
NAMED YOU "SCARY,"
- 嘿，我应该有
称你为“可怕”
EH, BUDDY?
呃，伙计？
- [mewing]
- [喵喵叫]
- SPONGEBOB,
THIS IS SERIOUS.
- 海绵宝宝，
这很严重。
I WAS JUST VICIOUSLY ATTACKED.
我刚刚遭到恶意攻击。
- [gasps]
NO.
- [喘气]
没有。
- YOU'VE GOT TO TEACH ME,
SPONGEBOB.
- 你必须教我，
海绵宝宝。
TEACH ME THE WAY.
教我方法。
THE WAY OF "TARA-KE".
“TARA-KE”之道。
- UH, DON'T YOU MEAN KARATE?
- 呃，你不是说空手道吗？
- UM, SURE.
WHATEVER.
- 嗯，当然。
任何。
- HMM.
HMM.
- 唔。
唔。
HMM, YES.
嗯，是的。
YOU SHOW POTENTIAL,
YOUNG STUDENT.
你展现出潜力，
年轻的学生。
BUT WITH THE RUBBERY ARMS,
但有了橡胶臂，
AND THE DOUGHINESS
IN THIS AREA,
和面团
在这个领域，
WE OBVIOUSLY HAVE
OUR WORK CUT OUT FOR US.
我们显然有
我们的工作为我们做好了准备。
- CAN'T WE JUST GET ON
WITH THIS, SPONGEBOB?
- 我们不能继续前进吗
有了这个，海绵宝宝？
- [shushing]
- [sighs]
- [嘘]
- [叹气]
I MEAN, CAN'T WE JUST
GET ON WITH THIS,
我的意思是，我们不能只是
继续这个，
OH, GREAT SENSEI?
噢，伟大的老师？
- PAY CLOSE ATTENTION,
AND YOU WILL RECEIVE
- 密切注意，
您将收到
THE TOTALITY
OF MY KARATE MASTERY.
整体性
我的空手道大师。
HANDED DOWN FROM
SENSEI CHEEKS HERSELF.
传承自
老师脸红了。
NOW WATCH,
现在看，
WATCH AND LEARN.
观看并学习。
WI-YAH!
威-亚！
- UH-HUH.
WHAT ELSE YOU GOT?
- 呃哈。
你还有什么？
- THAT'S IT.
- THAT'S IT?
- 就是这样。
- 就是这样？
THAT'S THE "TOTALITY
OF YOUR KARATE MASTERY"?
这就是“整体性”
你的空手道掌握程度”？
- WELL, SQUIDWARD,
I'VE ONLY BEEN STUDYING
- 嗯，章鱼哥，
我只是在学习
A COUPLE OF YEARS,
BUT IF TOTAL KARATE KNOWLEDGE
几年了，
但如果有完整的空手道知识
IS WHAT YOU SEEK--
这就是您所寻求的——
- THEN YOU SHOULD VISIT
SENSEI CHEEKS.
- 那么你应该参观
老师的脸颊。
- HEY, I WAS JUST
GOING TO SAY THAT!
- 嘿，我只是
我要这么说！
- I KNOW.
- 我知道。
[both laugh]
- OH, BOY.
[两人都笑了]
- 哦，男孩。
- I DON'T KNOW, SPONGEBOB.
- 我不知道，海绵宝宝。
WITH THE RUBBERY ARMS
AND THE DOUGHINESS
橡胶臂
和面团
IN THIS AREA,
WE OBVIOUSLY--
在这个领域，
我们显然——
- ALL RIGHT, ALREADY.
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH THIS.
- 好吧，已经了。
我们已经经历过这个了。
ARE YOU GOING TO TEACH ME
HOW TO GET REVENGE
你要教我吗
如何复仇
ON MY ATTACKER OR WHAT?
针对我的攻击者还是什么？
- WHOA-HO-HO.
KARATE AIN'T FOR REVENGE.
- 哇-嗬-嗬。
空手道不是为了复仇。
IT'S A DELICATE ART
THAT HELPS YOU PROTECT YOURSELF.
这是一门精致的艺术
这有助于您保护自己。
- YEAH, FINE.
- GREAT, REPEAT AFTER ME.
- 是的，很好。
- 太好了，跟我重复一遍。
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
- HI-YAH!
- 嗨呀！
- OH, WHATEVER.
- 哦，无论如何。
HI-YAH.
嗨呀。
- I PROMISE TO USE KARATE
ONLY FOR PROTECTION
- 我保证使用空手道
只为保护
AND NOT FOR REVENGE.
并不是为了复仇。
- I PROMISE TO USE KARATE
ONLY FOR PROTECTION
- 我保证使用空手道
只为保护
AND NOT FOR REVENGE.
并不是为了复仇。
OR WHATEVER.
或者无论什么。
- OKAY, THEN.
- 好吧，那么。
LET'S GET STARTED
WITH A LITTLE CHOPPING.
让我们开始吧
稍微切一下。
LIKE SO.
像这样。
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
- WHOA.
- 哇哦。
- A BOARD?
- 一块板？
I WASN'T ATTACKED
BY A PIECE OF WOOD.
我没有受到攻击
用一块木头。
I WAS ASSAULTED
BY A DERANGED LUNATIC.
我被侵犯了
一个精神错乱的疯子写的。
- THE ONLY WAY
YOU'LL PROTECT YOURSELF
- 唯一的方法
你会保护自己
IS IF YOU KNOW
THE BASICS.
如果你知道的话
基础知识。
NOW GIVE IT A CHOP.
现在就来试试吧。
- [sighs] WHATEVER
YOU SAY, SENSEI.
- [叹气] 无论如何
你说，老师。
- THIS IS A TOUGH ONE,
SQUIDWARD.
- 这是一场艰难的比赛，
章鱼哥。
DON'T FEEL BAD
IF YOU CAN'T DO IT.
别难过
如果你做不到。
- I'M SURE I CAN
BREAK ONE LITTLE TWIG.
- 我确信我可以
折断一根小树枝。
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
[crack]
[裂缝]
[splash]
[溅]
- ARMS UP, SQUIDWARD.
- 武装起来，章鱼哥。
BLOCK! BLOCK!
堵塞！堵塞！
- [grumbles]
THIS IS STUPID.
- [抱怨]
这太愚蠢了。
THE ONLY THING THIS MANIAC
THREW AT ME
这个疯子唯一的事
扔给我
WERE HIS BIG, MEATY FISTS.
是他的大拳头。
[grumbles]
[抱怨]
- BLOCK!
- 堵塞！
- NOW THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT.
- 现在你就这样做了。
- DIMWIT'S LUCK.
- 迪姆威特的运气。
[grumbles]
- COME ON, SQUIDDY.
[抱怨]
- 来吧，鱿鱼。
GIVE IT THE OLD ROUNDHOUSE.
给它旧的圆屋。
- ALL RIGHT.
- 好的。
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
[yelping]
[尖叫]
AAH!
啊啊！
THIS ISN'T WORKING.
这是行不通的。
MY ASSAILANT
WAS TWICE AS TALL.
我的攻击者
身高是原来的两倍。
AND HIS SHOULDERS
WERE 20 TIMES AS BROAD.
和他的肩膀
范围是原来的 20 倍。
THE FURROWS OF HIS BROW
WERE THE SIZE OF BICEPS.
他额头上的皱纹
有二头肌的大小。
- HMM.
- 唔。
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO MAKE THIS MORE PERSONAL
我们将会有
让这变得更加个性化
FOR YOU, SQUIDWARD,
为了你，章鱼哥，
SO AS TO HELP YOU
BRING OUT YOUR INNER DRAGON.
以便帮助您
释放你内心的龙。
SPONGEBOB?
海绵宝宝？
- HEY, GROCERY BOY!
- 嘿，杂货店男孩！
IT IS ME,
A BIG, SCARY MISCREANT.
这是我，
一个可怕的大恶棍。
NOW HAND OVER
THAT SACK OF GROCERIES
现在移交
那袋杂货
BEFORE THINGS GET UGLY.
在事情变得丑陋之前。
- GROCERIES?
- 杂货？
YOU'LL HAVE TO PULL
MY GROCERIES
你必须拉
我的杂货
FROM MY COLD,
WET TENTACLES, BUCKO.
由于我的感冒，
湿漉漉的触手，巴克。
TAKE THIS!
拿着这个！
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
HUH?
嗯？
THINK THAT'S GOING TO STOP ME?
你认为这会阻止我吗？
YOU'RE NOT GETTING ME
WITHOUT A FIGHT!
你不明白我的意思
无需战斗！
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
[struggling]
[挣扎]
GOT YOU RIGHT
WHERE I WANT YOU.
没错
我想要你在哪里。
VENGEANCE IS MINE.
复仇是我的。
- "VENGEANCE"?
- “复仇”？
SQUIDWARD TENTACLES,
I TOLD YOU AT THE BEGINNING
章鱼哥触手，
我一开始就告诉过你
THAT KARATE
AIN'T FOR REVENGE.
那个空手道
不是为了复仇。
SORRY, SQUIDWARD.
对不起，章鱼哥。
AS OF NOW,
I AIN'T YOUR SENSEI NO MORE.
截至目前，
我不再是你的老师了。
- SANDY, WAIT!
[struggles]
- 桑迪，等等！
[挣扎]
I NEED YOU TO TEACH--
我需要你来教——
OH, THIS IS POINTLESS.
哦，这毫无意义。
I'LL NEVER BE ABLE
TO PROTECT MYSELF.
我永远无法
保护我自己。
I MAY AS WELL JUST START HANDING
MY GROCERIES TO CRIMINALS.
我也可以开始处理
我的杂货给犯罪分子。
"HERE, PLEASE,
MR. CRIMINAL.
“这里，请
先生。犯罪。
TAKE MY UNPROCESSED
KALE CREAM."
拿我未处理的
羽衣甘蓝奶油。”
- SANDY, WAIT.
- 桑迪，等等。
PLEASE, HELP HIM.
请帮助他。
HE JUST WANTS TO KEEP
HIS ORGANIC BLUE ALGAE SAFE.
他只是想保留
他的有机蓝藻安全。
- HE'S GOING TO USE MY TEACHINGS
FOR REVENGE, SPONGEBOB.
- 他将使用我的教导
为了复仇，海绵宝宝。
- PLEASE, SANDY,
I'LL DO ANYTHING!
- 桑迪，拜托，
我会做任何事！
- OH, REALLY?
- 哦真的吗？
WELL, SQUIDWARD,
A WISE SENSEI ONCE TOLD ME
嗯，章鱼哥，
一位明智的老师曾经告诉我
ONE MUST FIRST KNOW
THE MOVEMENTS OF EVERY DAY
首先必须知道
每天的运动
BEFORE MASTERING KARATE.
在掌握空手道之前。
[button clicking]
[点击按钮]
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
[vacuum hums]
[真空嗡嗡声]
WHEW!
哇！
ALL FINISHED.
全部完成。
- WOW!
THIS LOOKS GREAT.
- 哇！
这看起来很棒。
- PSST.
YOU MISSED A SPOT.
- PSST。
你错过了一个地方。
- ALL RIGHT, I RECKON THE YARD
IS GOOD AND WATERED.
- 好吧，我算了一下院子
很好并且浇过水。
- PSST.
YOU MISSED A SPOT.
- PSST。
你错过了一个地方。
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
WHEW.
哇。
- ATTA BOY, SQUIDDY.
- 阿塔男孩，鱿鱼。
BE SURE TO TWIST THAT TORSO.
一定要扭转躯干。
- HEY, SANDY.
- 嘿，桑迪。
I DON'T REMEMBER THIS
BEING A PART OF MY TRAINING.
我不记得了
成为我训练的一部分。
IT WASN'T,
BUT TODAY IS CHORE DAY.
事实并非如此，
但今天是家务日。
SO I FIGURED WHY NOT
FRY TWO FISH IN ONE SKILLET.
所以我想为什么不呢
一锅煎两条鱼。
[both laugh]
[两人都笑了]
- THAT'S IT.
I AM OUTTA HERE!
- 就是这样。
我要离开这里！
THIS IS A NO GOOD
WASTE OF MY TIME.
这不好
浪费我的时间。
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
HEY, I'M DOING IT.
嘿，我正在做。
I'M BLOCKING THE ACORNS.
我正在阻止橡子。
- YEE-HAW!
I TOLD YOU ALL YOU HAD TO DO
- 呀呀！
我告诉了你所有你必须做的
WAS KNOW THE MOVEMENTS
OF EVERY DAY TO MASTER KARATE.
知道动作
每天掌握空手道。
- [laughs]
I CAN'T BELIEVE I DID IT!
- [笑]
我不敢相信我做到了！
- YEAH! YEAH!
NOW TRY THIS!
- 是的！是的！
现在试试这个！
- OKAY,
OKAY.
- 好吧，
好的。
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
- [laughs]
I DID IT!
- [笑]
我做到了！
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
I CAN PROTECT
MY GROCERIES NOW!
我可以保护
我的杂货现在！
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
[crash]
[碰撞]
I AM A KARATE MASTER.
我是空手道大师。
WHOO-HOO-HOO!
呼呼呼！
- WELL,
I WOULDN'T GO THAT FAR,
- 嗯，
我不会走那么远，
BUT YOU HAVE PROVEN
YOURSELF WORTHY OF
但你已经证明了
你自己值得
THE BELT
OF BASIC COMPETENCE.
腰带
的基本能力。
- YEAH, YEAH.
THAT'S GREAT, THANKS.
- 是啊是啊。
太好了，谢谢。
BUT I HAVE SOME BUSINESS
TO ATTEND TO.
但我还有事
参加。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
WHAT'S THIS?
这是什么？
DO I FIND MYSELF ON THIS
DARK AND SCARY STREET
我在这方面找到了自己吗
黑暗恐怖的街道
YET AGAIN?
又来了？
WE'LL JUST SEE
WHAT HAPPENS THIS TIME.
我们拭目以待
这次会发生什么。
- HEY, YOU!
- 嘿，你！
- LET ME GIVE A TASTE,
A MERE MORSEL
- 让我尝尝，
一点点
OR WHAT'S IN STORE.
或者有什么。
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
THAT ONE WAS CALLED
"WASHING SANDY'S WINDOWS".
那一个被称为
“清洗桑迪的窗户”。
STAY BACK
OR YOU'RE GOING TO GET IT.
退后一步
否则你就会得到它。
I AM WARNING YOU.
我警告你。
- [wheezing]
- [喘息]
- OKAY, BUDDY.
I WARNED YOU.
- 好吧，伙计。
我警告过你。
I LIKE TO CALL THIS ONE
"TAKING OUT SANDY'S TRASH".
我喜欢称呼这个为
“倒掉桑迪的垃圾”。
HI-YAH!
嗨呀！
- WHAT? OW!
- 什么？噢！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
HOW DO YOU LIKE
THEM APPLES?
你觉得怎么样
他们是苹果吗？
WAAH!
哇啊！
- OH! OW!
- 哦！噢！
- HA, FEEL MY WRATH.
- 哈，感受我的愤怒。
HOW'S YOUR UNCLE?
你叔叔怎么样？
- OW! OW.
- 噢！哦。
- AND, AS MY FINISHING MOVE,
I GIVE YOU
- 而且，作为我的最后一步，
我给你
"WATERING SANDY'S LAWN".
“给桑迪的草坪浇水”。
BEE-YAH!
哎呀！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
HEY, MAN.
WH-WHAT WAS THAT FOR?
嘿，伙计。
那是什么？
I WAS JUST TRYING TO
GIVE YOU BACK
我只是想
还给你
YOUR GROCERIES
YOU DROPPED.
你的杂货
你掉队了。
- UH, OH.
- 呃，哦。
- SANDY, I FOUND HIM.
HE'S OVER HERE.
- 桑迪，我找到他了。
他在这儿。
YOU FORGOT
YOUR BELT, SILLY.
你忘记了
你的腰带，傻瓜。
[gasps]
[喘气]
- GOSH,
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
- 天哪，
你怎么了？
- THIS GUY'S BEEN KARATE'D.
- 这家伙学过空手道。
- AFTER ALL I SAID ABOUT NEVER
USING KARATE FOR REVENGE?
- 毕竟我说过从来没有
用空手道复仇？
- FOR SHAME, SQUIDWARD.
FOR SHAME.
- 耻辱，章鱼哥。
耻辱。
- LOOKS LIKE HE'S NOT WORTHY
OF THIS BELT AFTER ALL.
- 看起来他不值得
毕竟是这条腰带。
THANKS FOR DISHONORING
OUR TRUST IN YOU, SQUIDWARD.
感谢您的羞辱
我们信任你，章鱼哥。
- WHATEVER.
I'M STILL A KARATE MASTER.
- 任何。
我仍然是空手道大师。
- WOW, REALLY?
YOU ARE?
- 哇，真的吗？
你是？
- YES, I AM.
- 我是。
- HEY, WATCH YOUR HEAD.
- 嘿，小心你的头。
I'D NEVER GUESS IT.
我绝对猜不到。
- AND WHAT IS THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
-那是什么
应该是什么意思？
- OH, UH, NOTHING.
- 哦，呃，没什么。
JUST WITH THE RUBBERY ARMS,
只需使用橡胶臂，
AND THE DOUGHINESS
IN THE MIDSECTION--
和面团
在中间部分——
- OKAY, ALREADY,
I GET IT.
- 好的，已经，
我明白了。
WHAT, WAIT A SECOND.
AM I UNDER ARREST?
什么，等一下。
我被捕了吗？
- YOU SURE ARE.
- 你确实是。
AND YOU HAVE THE RIGHT
TO REMAIN SILENT...
你有权利
保持沉默...
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- OR NOT SILENT.
- 或者不保持沉默。